SUBHASH TALLURI

480-410-0824

https://subhashtalluri.github.io

subhash.talluri@outlook.com

SUMMARY

Trained mechanical engineer. Experienced Aerospace engineer. Passionate data scientist. IoT Enthusiast. Cloud Architect

SKILLS

Data Science - Python (8), R (7), SQL (5), Tableau (6), Spark (beginner), Big Data Ecosystem (beginner)

Cloud - AWS Certified - Solutions Architect, ML Specialty & Big Data Specialty
Domain - Experience in Telecom, Expertise in Aerospace, Industrial & Manufacturing

Comp. Science - Full Stack, SDLC, Agile, Git Versioning, Linux CLI

Strengths - Supervised/Unsupervised, Pattern Mining, Anomaly Detection, Time Series, Bayesian Inference, Optimization

Improving On - Deep Learning (NLP, Image, Vision), Reinforcement Learning, Transfer Learning, Robotics

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Amazon Web Services

Sr. Partner Solutions Architect – AI / ML Practice

Atlanta, GA | Dec 2019 - Present

- Help clients and partners build scalable, secure and compliant AI/ML solutions via cloud optimized architectures on AWS
- Develop industry solutions with ISVs & consulting partners. Build mind share, establish partner trust and nurture adoption of AWS cloud computing platform.
- Author reference architectures & whitepapers. Deliver technical webinars, speak at public events and file patents

Capgemini America

Lead Data Scientist / Delivery Architect

Atlanta, GA | Nov 2018 - Nov 2019

- Experienced in providing predictive analytics for transaction reduction in the cable industry
- Experience in designing and implementing data science architectures within the business framework
- Expertise in taking business requirements & defining ML problem framework
- Experience implementing ML@ scale and taking ML to production (Kafka Streams, Spark Processing, Hive/HBase: Beginner)
- Responsible for developing analytics strategy, use case identification, proof-of-concepts & end-to-end execution for true ROI

Cyient Insights

Data Scientist, Aerospace & Defense

Chandler, AZ | Sept 2017 - Nov 2018

- Developed predictive analytics solutions for the aerospace industry (health monitoring & diagnostics Anomaly detection)
- Adept at data wrangling, data visualization & machine learning model development (supervised, pattern mining, clustering)
- Responsibilities:
 - Identifying and managing the analysis and implementation of client's internal and external data to drive decision making
 - Query databases and perform statistical mathematical analysis.
 - Create reusable implementations of statistical tests and ML models (R, Python etc.) using available technologies
 - Assist in customer engagement management, project scoping, budgeting & time-line management
 - Define solution architectures using engineering knowledge and translate executive requests, questions, concerns or ideas into successful data science implementations.

Pratt & Whitney Canada

Analyst, Material/Structural

Mississauga, Ontario | Dec 2010 - Sept 2017

- Experienced in gas turbine engine development from concept design, first engine test and certification to production phase
- Specialist in design, structural & dynamic analysis, impact & fracture mechanics, fatigue life evaluation, structural testing
- Expert in physics-based modeling numerical methods (FEM), mathematical simulations & design optimization
- Experienced in manufacturing & production technology, MRB activities & process root cause analysis
- Expertise in full engine & component rig tests to support internal engine development & analytical methods validation
- Experienced in writing certification reports for regulating authorities such as Transport Canada, FAA & EASA

EDUCATION

University Degree	University	Year
MBA, Global Strategy	University of Illinois – Gies College of Business	2022
MS, Computer Science – Data Science	University of Illinois Urbana Champaign	2019
MS, Aerospace Science & Engineering	University of Toronto, Canada	2010
BS, Mechanical Engineering	Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University	2008